

□ (808)232-8467 | 💌 Taha@hawaii.edu | 🎁 tahahojati.github.io | 🖸 tahahojati | 🛅 taha-pourjalali-2a2600b8

Summary _

Recent university graduate with experience in programming and web and database design. In possession of strong written communication skills and ability to establish interpersonal relationships with teams and clients. The links to some of my projects (listed in this document) are present on my portfolio page at tahahojati.github.io.

Education ___

Henry J. Kaiser High school

Honolulu, HI

Diploma with Honors

2010 - 2011

University of Hawai'i at Mānoa

Honolulu, HI

B.S. in Physics

Udacity.com

2011 - 2016

• Membership in the Society of Physics Students and the Golden Key Honor Society.

Honolulu, HI

Nanodegree in Front-End Development

2016

Skills _____

Programming PHP, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Ruby, Python, Perl, HTML, CSS

Frameworks Zend Framework 1, Ruby on Rails, ExpressJs, AngularJs, Ionic, Bootstrap, KnockoutJs

IDEs & Development Tools Adobe Dreamweaver, PHP Storm, Eclipse IDE, Git, Gulp, Jasmin, PHPUnit, RSpec, Cucumber

Softwares & Databases Apache, Rack, MySQL, PostgreSQL, phpMyAdmin

Projects _____

OPIHI: Our Project in Hawaii's Intertidal (under active development)

Designed a science education database schema using MySQL. Developed a server-side web application using Zend Framework, Angular.js, and Apache2.

AASHTO LRFD DESIGN Online Software (under active development)

A website with the purpose of structural engineering design using an online software. The website is being developed using Zend Framework.

Ristorante con Fusion

Developed a single page web application for a fictitious restaurant using Angular.js and Bootstrap. Also created a hybrid mobile app for the restaurant using Ionic and Cordova.

Coffee in Honolulu

Displayed a map of coffee shops in Honolulu using Knockout.js framework and Google Maps and FourSquare APIs.

Wrote a JavaScript version of the classic arcade game Frogger. Made extensive use of object oriented JavaScript.

Experience _

Curriculum Research and Development Group at University of Hawai'i at Mānoa

Honolulu, HI

Web and Database Developer

Apr 2016 - present

• Software developer for the OPIHI project.

University of Hawai'i at Mānoa

Honolulu, HI

2014

• Worked closely with students to deepen their knowledge of physics.

Department of Physics University of Hawai'i at Mānoa

Honolulu, HI

Directed Studies Under Dr. Vahsen

2013

• Devised an app with graphical user interface to select, display, and graph neutron trajectories identified by a neutron detector using C++ and ROOT under the guidance of Dr. Sven Vahsen.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Honolulu, HI

2011-2013

Department of Molecular Biosciences and Bioengineering at University of Hawaiʻi at Mānoa

- Created a database of retro-transposons in Corn genome using MySQL and Perl.
- Created a website to expose the database to public using PHP5 and Appache2.